[ORGANISER] Andreas Antonopoulos! [Applause]
[组织者]安德烈亚斯·安东尼奥普洛斯！ [掌声]
[ANDREAS] It is such a huge pleasure to be here today. This is such a great community.
[安德烈亚斯]今天很高兴来到这里。 这是一个很棒的社区
Everyone here welcomed me with such warmth and open arms, so thank you!
这里的每个人都这样热情和张开双臂欢迎我，谢谢！
Thank you so much for having me here tonight.
非常感谢您今晚能过来
I would like to talk about a couple important issues [regarding] regulatory legitimacy.
我想谈谈有关监管合法性的几个重要问题
The cryptocurrency space can achieve compliance with the payment card industry (PCI) standard...
加密货币领域可以实现合规符合支付卡行业（PCI）的标准...
and Sarbanes-Oxley's Public Company Accounting Oversight Board (PCAOB).
以及萨班斯·奥克斯利的上市公司 会计监督委员会（PCAOB）的要求
[We can incorporate] 'Know-Your-Customer' (KYC) and the anti-money laundering (AML) rules,
[我们可以做到]“了解您的客户”（KYC） 以及反洗钱（AML）规则，
which will allow us to achieve legitimacy with bankers and [gain] our position on the world stage...
这将使我们能够在银行家们面前获得合法性，并[获得]我们在世界舞台上的地位...
as a trusted, legitimate currency. [Laughter] [Applause]
作为一种值得信赖的合法货币。 [笑声] [掌声]
Eh, fuck that! [Laughter [Applause] No, I don't want to talk about that. Who wants to talk about that?
嗯，去他的吧！ [笑声][掌声] 不，我不想谈这个。谁想谈这个？
[That stuff] is ridiculous. We don't need any legitimacy. We are having fun. We deal with more serious issues.
[那些东西]太荒谬了。我们不需要任何合法性。我们玩的很开心。我们得处理更紧急的问题
There are a lot of serious people in Wall Street: dour faced, boring, soulless, parasitic people...
华尔街有很多严肃的人： 阴沉，无聊，没有灵魂，寄生的人...
wearing suits and ties.
都穿着西装，打着领带
Guess what? They stole trillions of dollars and got away with it. Who needs their legitimacy? [Applause]
你猜怎么着？他们偷走了数万​​亿美元，却安然无恙。谁需要他们提供的合法性？ [掌声]
I want to talk about things that are warm to my heart.
我想谈一谈温暖我心灵的事情
Some of you may have heard the talks I have given recently, about currency as a language.
你们中有些人可能听过我的演讲， 在演讲中我声称货币是一种语言
Has anyone here heard some of those talks?
这里有人听过这些演讲吗？
Not many people, great. It will all sound brand new to you, a great opportunity for me to repeat myself.
人数不多，很好。对您来说，这一切听起来都是全新的，这是我重申观点的绝好机会
What I care about is charity and the other six billion.
我关心的是慈善事业，地球上另外的60亿人
There are a billion people in this world who have access to bank accounts without currency controls,
这个世界上有十​​亿人 可以在没有货币管制的情况下使用银行帐户，
that can transmit money in international markets and access deep pools of liquid credit for loans.
可以在国际市场上转移资金， 并获得大量的流动性信贷贷款
[That is] us, the rich people of the Western world.
那[就是]我们，西方世界的有钱人
Then there is the other six billion people worn all around the world who have limited bank accounts...
然后还有世界各地另外60亿人， 他们的银行帐户服务受到限制...
or no bank accounts at all.
或根本没有银行帐户
People who live on $1 per day if they are lucky.
如果他们够幸运的话，可以每天靠1美元就能生活
People who have no access to international markets, no access to international finance, no access to loans.
他们无法进入国际市场, 无法获得国际融资，无法获得贷款
No access to opportunity.
无法获得机会
I would like to think that I am a really smart guy who got here because of efforts I made throughout my life,
我认为我是一个非常聪明的人 因为我一生都在努力
but we all know that is bullshit.
但是我们都知道那是胡扯
I got here through an accident of birth,
我的出身是随机的
which put me in a white middle-class society of the developed nation of Greece.
这让我置身于希腊这个发达国家的白人中产阶级社会
As a child of professional, educated parents, I was swimming with current all the way.
作为受过专业教育的孩子， 我的人生一帆风顺
There are hundreds of thousands of people smarter than me, dying of diphtheria somewhere in the world.
而世界上有成千上万比我更聪明的人死于白喉病
I care about what we could do with cryptocurrencies to bring economic development and inclusion.
我关心的是我们如何利用加密货币来促进经济发展和包容
[I care about] bringing the other six billion [people] into a world economy without borders, political corruption,
[我关心]的是将其他60亿人带入一个 没有边界，没有政治腐败的世界经济
and massive theft by parasitic banks. [Applause]
以及消灭寄生银行的大规模盗窃行为。 [掌声]
And it starts with charity at a very basic level.
它从一个非常基本的层面开始
This community [speaks about] charity more than any other cryptocurrency community.
我们这个社区比其他任何加密货币社区都更多地谈论慈善
Thank you so much for leading the way and [being] an example of what we can do with cryptocurrency,
非常感谢您的领导， 并成为我们使用加密货币的一个榜样
when we think [about] doing good.
当我们想要做公益的时候的榜样
That is what is amazing about this community.
这就是这个社区的神奇之处
Bitcoin has a lot of charity too. We have achieved some amazing things in the Bitcoin space [through charity].
比特币也有很多慈善事业。我们已经取得了一些成就:[通过慈善]在比特币领域带来了令人惊奇的成就
About a month and a half ago, Newsweek destroyed the life of an innocent old man called Dorian Nakamoto,
大约一个半月前，《新闻周刊》毁了 一个无辜的、名叫多里安·中本聪的老人的生活，
by saying that he was the creator of this currency.
说他是这种货币的创造者
I started a fundraiser; within six hours, we raised more than thirty bitcoin for Dorian, Nakamoto.
我发起了募捐活动；在六个小时内，我们为中本聪多里安（Dorian）募集了三十多个比特币
Now, we have raised almost fifty bitcoin to help this man put his life together [again].
现在，我们已经筹集了将近五十个比特币 帮助这个人重新生活
At the same time, Sean's Outpost, one of my favourite major charities, distributed sixty-five thousand meals...
同时，肖恩的前哨基地，我最喜欢的慈善机构之一，分发了六万五千顿饭...
for the homeless of Pensacola, Florida in the last year.
去年为佛罗里达州彭萨科拉（Pensacola）的无家可归者提供帮助
[They] tapped into Bitcoin and used it to raise money from people all around the world.
[他们]利用比特币从世界各地的人们那里筹集资金
If people care, they can now send money anywhere in the world to support the charity of their choice.
如果人们关心这些，他们现在可以汇款到世界上任何一个地方支持他们选择的慈善事业
[Applause] When there was a typhoon in the Philippines, Fr33aid raised money and set over $5,000 within a day.
[鼓掌]菲律宾有台风时， Fr33aid筹集了资金，一天之内就筹集了超过5,000美元
[The money went] right on the ground where it mattered, where it could make a difference in people's lives...
[这笔钱]正好花在重要的地方 它可以改变人们的生活...
without having to worry about regulations, [slow] wire transfers, or giving Western Union a 20% cut.
不用担心监管，[缓慢]的电汇流程， 以及西联汇款20％的手续费用
All of these charities take [bitcoin as] a currency and turning it into a force for good.
所有这些慈善机构都将[比特币]作为一种货币，并将其转变为一种向善的力量
But that is only the beginning.
但这仅仅是开始
We have the opportunity to subvert and improve some of the most exploited markets in the world.
我们有机会颠覆和改​​进一些世界上最受剥削的市场
The first one I care about a lot is the international remittances market.
我最关心的第一个市场是国际汇款市场
Every year, poor people in the developed world who are migrants and have jobs as itinerant workers...
每年，发达国家的穷人，那些流动工人、移民
[They are mostly] Mexicans here in the United States; Indians in different places like Dubai, for construction...
[他们主要是]美国的墨西哥人； 印度人、迪拜人，从事建设工作；
They send money home to their families abroad. $500 billion [in total] primarily goes to four countries:
他们将钱寄回家给国外的家人。 [总计] 5,000亿美元主要流向四个国家：
Mexico, the Philippines, Indonesia, and India.
墨西哥，菲律宾，印度尼西亚和印度
That $500 billion is a lot more than what we in the developed world send in terms of financial aid.
这5000亿美元远远超过了我们发达国家发送财政援助
Approximately $175 billion has been sent by our governments to the developing world.
我们各国政府想发展中国家提供的援助大概是1750亿美元
Guess where that money goes? [Financial aid] from our government goes to the top of their governments...
猜猜这些钱花到哪里去了？ 这些来自 我们的政府的[经济援助]一旦发送给他们的政府...
and then trickles down.
就会跑冒滴漏
Only about 5% actually reaches the people in need because the rest is taken through corruption.
实际上只有约5％的钱到达了需要帮助的人手里，其余的都被贪污掉了
Meanwhile, out of the $500 billion sent through remittances, $75 billion is collected as fees...
同时，在汇款过程中，收取了750亿美元的手续费...
by companies like Western Union.
由Western Union等公司收取
They charge anywhere from 5% to more than 25% on the money that people are sending home to their families.
他们会对人们寄回家给家人的钱收取5％至25％以上的费用
That is $75 billion [taken] out of the pockets of the poorest people on this planet. We can change that.
这是从这个星球上最贫穷的人手中夺取的750亿美元。我们可以改变这一点
We can change that right now.
我们现在就可以改变
Cryptocurrencies enable flows of money from the developed nations to the developing world,
加密货币使资金流从发达国家流向发展中国家，
to give back that $75 billion to the people who need it most.
把这750亿美元退还给最需要它的人
If you take that money [back] and put it in the pockets of the poorest people in the world,
如果您把这笔钱还给世界上最贫穷的人
specifically the pockets of women who run the finances in their communities,
特别是在他们的社区里经营财务的女性
[receiving] money from their husbands and family members abroad, they will convert every single dollar...
她们[从丈夫和家人那里收到钱]，她们将把每一美元用来...
[into improving] water [access], sanitation, education, and healthcare.
[改善]水[获取]，卫生，教育和医疗保健
They have an immediate impact that reaches very far in their own community. That is how we change the world.
这对他们自己的社区产生了直接的深远影响。这就是我们改变世界的方式
That is what we can do with cryptocurrencies. That is what I care about. [Applause]
那就是我们可以使用加密货币做的事情。 这就是我所关心的。 [掌声]
One of the questions I have been thinking about for the last year is, how do altcoins behave against each other?
我去年一直在思考的问题之一是：山寨币是如何相互竞争的？
Whether they are in competition or not. The underlying question is one of scarcity.
不管他们有没有竞争， 根本问题是在于资源稀缺
A lot of people think other coins compete directly with bitcoin, and if there are too many coins,
许多人认为其他山寨币直接与比特币竞争币，如果山寨太多，
that dilutes the value and digital scarcity created by bitcoin.
就会稀释比特币创造的价值和稀缺性
I think that is a very old fashioned way to look at currency. We think of currency that way because...
我认为这是一种非常老式的看待货币的观点。我们之所以这样看待货币，是因为...
Throughout our lives, we have grown up in a world...
在我们的一生中，我们成长在这样一个世界...
of national sovereign currencies that exist in a monopolistic zero-sum game.
存在于垄断零和博弈中的国家主权货币
Winning for my currency and my nation is a zero-sum game against [another nation's] currency.
为我的货币和国家赢得胜利是对[另一个国家的]货币的零和游戏
All these currencies exhibit a [geo-political] monopoly. If I live in the United States, I am born into U.S. dollars.
所有这些货币都表现出[地缘政治]垄断， 如果我居住在美国，我出生在美元国家
I don't have a choice. I must pay my taxes in U.S. dollars, and that is the currency I will use [while I'm there].
我别无选择，我必须用美元纳税 这就是我[在那里时]将使用的货币
Well, [some of] that is no longer the case. [Because of Bitcoin], currency is now a choice.
好吧，[某些]情况已不再如此。 [由于比特币]，货币现在是一种选择
With these digital currencies created by individuals, we can now choose any currency we want to interact with.
利用个人创建的这些数字货币，我们现在可以选择任何我们所喜欢的货币
In making that choice, we also choose our community and the currency which best represents our values.
在做出选择时，我们还选择了我们的社区 和最能代表我们价值观的货币
[That choice] is more powerful than any vote in the world.
[这个选择]比世界上任何投票都更有力量
Let's think about what it means to choose a currency and how that currency derives value.
让我们思考一下选择的含义: 选择一种货币，该货币如何产生价值
We need to re-think the word. Currency used to be defined by the authority of the sovereign who created it.
我们需要重新考虑这个词。货币曾经是 由创建它的主权者的权威来定义的
The sovereign who created the currency would put the force and monopoly of the state behind it...
创造货币的主权者会将国家的力量和垄断置于背后...
to give it value, and that is what gave currency value in the old world.
赋予它价值，这就是旧世界货币价值的来源
In this world, a cryptocurrency with a funny dog [as its mascot] has value. Why? Because it has value to you.
在这个世界上，一种使用一只可爱的狗狗[作为吉祥物]的加密货币也有价值。为什么？因为它对您有价值
You give it value by using that currency.
您可以使用该货币为其赋予价值
What happens in ten or fifteen years as cryptocurrencies become more widespread?
十年或十五年后会发生什么? 加密货币会变得越来越普遍吗？
How do you look at value in a world where anybody can create a currency?
在一个任何人都可以创建货币的世界里，您如何看待其价值？
What does it mean if, someday, you [travel to] a rural environment in Africa,
如果有一天，您[旅行]至非洲的乡村
which is predominantly using two currencies:
那里主要使用两种货币：
one has a funny dog, and the other has an old white woman named Elizabeth.
一种货币的吉祥物是一只狗狗， 另一种货币的图腾则是叫伊丽莎白的老白人妇女
Well, I can tell you something. The people in that village probably don't know who Elizabeth is.
好吧，我可以告诉你一些事情。 那个村庄里的人可能不知道伊丽莎白是谁
They will certainly have no clue what the hell that dog is and why its eyes look like that. [Laughter]
他们也肯定不会知道那只狗是什么，为什么它的眼睛看起来像那样。 [笑声]
What they do know: you could use either one of these currencies to buy six eggs.
他们所知道的是：您可以使用一种货币买六个鸡蛋
That is all that matters. If a currency is useful as a means of exchange, then that currency has value.
这才是最重要的。如果货币作为交换手段是有用的，那么意味着该货币就有价值
You can have a thousand economists write a thousand PhD papers that tell you exactly why it's not a currency.
你可以让一千个经济学家写一千篇博士论文来告诉您为什么它不是货币
But if you can buy six eggs, then it is a currency and nothing else matters.
但是如果你能买六个鸡蛋，那就是货币， 其他一切都不重要
What is the fundamental difference between currencies if they have monetary value at the point of purchase?
如果货币在购买时就具有货币价值， 那么货币之间的根本区别是什么？
If they can be used to exchange for goods and services by people in a community who will use that currency?
如果它可以被一个社区的人用来交换商品和服务，那么谁会先来使用这种货币呢？
Well, one of the currencies has a predictable, deterministic, fixed monetary supply.
嗯，其中一种货币具有可预测的、 确定性的固定货币供应
The other currency has an old white lady on the front. That is the only difference.
另一种货币有一位老白人女士印在上面。 那是唯一的区别
They sure as hell didn't pick that currency and they don't know why Elizabeth is on it.
他们肯定不会选择那种货币， 他们不知道为什么伊丽莎白在上面
Maybe she won a popularity contest. Well, so did the dog. [Laughter]
也许她赢得了一次人气选秀大赛， 好吧，那只狗也一样。 [笑声]
We now live in the world where currency acquires value through its use.
我们现在生活的世界是， 货币通过使用获得价值
If you can transact internationally with a currency, the only thing that matters is how many people use it,
如果您可以使用货币进行国际交易， 唯一重要的是有多少人使用它，
and how they use that currency.
以及他们如何使用该货币
If they use that currency, that gives it value, by definition.
如果他们使用该货币， 那么根据定义，这将为其赋予价值
How do we survive in that kind of world where value is determined purely by adoption, not by a sovereign.
这个世界的货币价值， 完全由市场决定，而不是由君主决定
Not by the regulations that back it, but by the algorithms that run it.
不是靠法规支持，而是通过运行它的算法支持
Not by trust in the central authority with the ability to print as much money as it wants,
不需要依靠中央权威， 以前他们想印多少钱就因多少钱，
who hands that money over at 0% interest to the biggest banks, in trickle-down economics.
以前的经济学中，他们把这些钱以0%的利率交给最大的银行
By algorithms that are predictable, deterministic, and remove uncertainty.
现在我们通过可预测的算法， 确定性，并消除不确定性
By algorithms that allow us to see how the currency will develop over time.
通过算法，我们可以看到货币将随着时间流逝如何改变发行量
In that world, adoption is the only thing that matters. We don't know how to live in that world.
在那个世界上，适者生存是唯一重要的事情。我们现在还不知道如何在那个世界里生存
That world hasn't come yet, but I think it is coming and coming fast.
那个世界还没有到来， 但我认为它离我们越来越近
I think the idea of [only having 180 national] currencies will seem quaint in a couple of decades.
我认为，[仅拥有180种国家/地区的货币]的观点在几十年后看起来会过时
In fact, until recently, I thought we would only have a couple hundred altcoins, and I changed my mind.
实际上，直到最近，我还认为我们只会有几百个山寨币，我改变了看法了
Guess what? I am often wrong.
你猜怎么了？我经常犯错
But when I get new facts, I form new opinions, because the old opinions don't fit the facts anymore.
但是当我得到新的事实时，我会形成新的见解，因为旧的观点不再适合事实
As I saw the explosion of alternative currencies, which in itself is a somewhat patronizing [term]...
当我看到替代货币的爆炸式增长时， 它本身是一个有点屈尊俯就的术语
As I saw the development of altcoins, I realized that we will not just have hundreds of currencies.
当我看到山寨币的发展时，我意识到我们将不仅拥有数百种货币
Let's do a quick poll. How many of you think that, in a decade, we will have hundreds of coins?
让我们进行一个简单的调查。有多少人认为，十年后，我们将拥有数百种货币？
Thousands? Tens of thousands? Hundreds of thousands? Millions?
还是几千种？成千上万种？ 数十万种？百万种？
All right, now we are having a conversation.
好吧，现在我们正在谈论这个
What does it mean to live in the world with hundreds of thousands or millions of currencies?
生活在拥有数十万或数百万货币的世界里意味着什么？
The key realization came when I saw a website that allowed me to build a cryptocurrency...
当我看到一个允许我建立一种加密货币的网站时，我意识到这个问题...
by entering a name and monetary policy from a drop-down box in a web form, and [clicking] 'submit.'
在Web表单中的下拉框中输入货币名称和发行政策，然后单击[提交]
You needed to pay about $50 to do that,
为此，您只需要支付约50美元，就得到一种新的加密货币
but I guarantee that by the end of the year, you will be able to do that for free.
但我保证到今年年底， 您将可以免费这样做
Then I realized that everybody will do it. At a very basic level, currency is a language.
然后我意识到每个人都会这样做。 从根本上讲，货币是一种语言
Currency is a means of expression.
货币是一种表达手段
Currency is the language by which we communicate value to each other.
货币是我们彼此交流价值的语言
Currency is an emergent artifact of a social species.
货币是一种社会物种的新兴产物
Let me repeat that: currency is an emergent artifact of a social species.
让我重复一遍：货币是一种社会物种的自然产物
How do you know that? Observe five year-olds.
你怎么知道的？观察五岁的孩子
Go into a primary school, watch how five-year-olds behave. They don't have currency, so they invent it.
走进小学，看五岁的孩子们的表现。他们没有货币，所以他们发明了货币
They invent currency as soon as they develop social bonds within a broad social environment.
只要他们在广泛的社会环境中形成了社会纽带，他们就会发明货币
If you go into a primary school, you will see children trading cards, Pokémon, Tamagotchi, rubber bands,
如果您走进一所小学，将会看到孩子交换卡片，神奇宝贝，电子鸡，橡皮筋，
candy, cafeteria credits, whatever.
糖果，自助餐厅积分，等等
It is not unlike a prison, in many ways. [Laughter]
在许多方面，它与监狱没有什么不同。 [笑声]
The only difference is, they don't allow them to have cigarettes.
唯一的区别是，它们不让他们抽烟
Otherwise, that would be the predominant currency.
否则，那将是主要货币
But they do allow them to have doughnuts; in many schools, that is the predominant currency.
但是他们确实允许他们吃甜甜圈。 在许多学校中，这是主要货币
Currency emerges in social environments because it is used by individuals to express value, appreciation,
货币出现在社会环境中，是因为它被个人用来表达价值，欣赏，
to express popularity and strengthen social bonds, to create social experiences.
表达声望并加强社会纽带，创造社会体验
That is what currency does. Trade is a social interaction.
这就是货币的作用。 贸易是一种社会互动
Currency is the language that allows us to have that social interaction.
货币是允许我们进行社交互动使用的语言
When children are able to create currency, that means everyone can create currency.
当孩子们能够创造货币时， 这意味着每个人都可以创造货币
There will be a JoeyCoin competing with MariaCoin in the primary school, in a battle of popularity.
小学里将会有一个JoeyCoin与MariaCoin的人气大战
Yes, there will be. There will be BieberCoin and MetallicaCoin. You can see how old I am. [Laughter]
是的，会有。将有BieberCoin和MetallicaCoin。你可以看到我多大了。 [笑声]
Maybe AndreasCoin. I will pre-mine the hell out of it.
也许是AndreasCoin。 我一定会把它挖出来的
There will be coins of all types, representing brands, corporations, your local mall, used as a loyalty card.
将将有各种类型的货币，代表各种品牌， 公司（您当地的购物中心）用作会员卡
There will be coins representing bands and silly memes. I am at a conference for one of those [right now].
将有代表乐队和搞笑表情包的货币。 我正在参加其中一个会议
It doesn't matter. All of these coins may or may not have [some value].
没关系；所有这些货币可能有价值， 也可能没有[价值]
But realize that there is a big difference between monetary value and [other forms of value].
但是要意识到，货币价值和[其他价值形式]两者之间有很大的不同
The vast majority of the tens of thousands of coins which may exist, will have no monetary value.
可能存在的数以万计的货币中的绝大多数都没有货币价值
You can try telling Joey that his coin doesn't have [monetary] value; it has value to Joey and his friends.
您可以尝试告诉乔伊:他的货币没有[货币价值]; 它只对乔伊和他的朋友们很有价值
It can be used to express popularity in a social market. It has value to the followers of [Justin] Bieber.
它可以用来表达在社交市场中的受欢迎程度。它对[Justin] Bieber的追随者具有价值
In some cases, it may [be more valuable] than some of the national currencies out there, if he ever launches it.
在某些情况下，如果特朗普发行货币， 他可能会比一些国家货币更有价值
How do we live in the world where there are hundreds of thousands of coins, and most of them have no value?
我们如何生活在这样一个世界？ 这个世界里有成千上万的货币，其中大多数却没有价值
We disassociate value from authority.
我们需要将价值与权威分离
We understand that value does not derive from who created it, but only from who is using it.
我们了解价值并非源自谁创造了它， 而是取决于谁在使用它
We already live in that world in terms of information.
我们已经生活在信息化的世界中
We used to [read] published opinion as being authoritative if it came from a publisher...
我们过去如何确定一个观点是权威的？ 如果来自初版商，则是权威的...
with a giant printing press and a fancy name, like the New York Times.
他们有一台巨型印刷机和一个花哨的名字， 像《纽约时报》
Then we [transitioned] to a world where everyone on the street could publish an opinion.
然后我们[过渡]到一个这样的世界 ： 大街上的每个人都可以发表意见
We needed to revise our understanding of authority, because it no longer fit the facts.
我们需要修改我们对权威的定义， 因为它不再符合事实
Sometimes, people from very esteemed institutions like the New York Times, such as "journalist" Judith Miller,
有时候，来自知名机构的人，比如纽约时报的“新闻工作者”朱迪思·米勒（Judith Miller），
lie about weapons of mass destruction (WMDs) in Iraq,
会在关于伊拉克大规模杀伤性武器这种话题上撒谎
[a lie which] kills hundreds of thousands of people.
[一个谎言]杀死数十万人
Sometimes, an Egyptian blogger, a nobody, tells the truth about the regime of Mubarak, because they are there.
有时候，一个埃及博主，一个无名小卒，会说出关于穆巴拉克政权的实话，因为他们就住在那里
We live in a world where [value] comes from the content, not from the authority of the printing press.
我们生活在一个[价值]来自内容的世界中， 价值并非来自印刷机的授权
And now we just did that to currency.
现在，我们只是将其转换为货币
Currency gains [value] not because of who created it, but by who uses it.
货币收益[价值]不是因为是由谁创造的， 而是由谁使用来决定
In a few decades, you might be surprised about which currency [achieved] monetary value status.
几十年后，您可能会对哪种货币[实现]货币价值地位感到惊讶
It will be a very grey line.
这将是一条非常灰的线
I think we will see currencies that suddenly erupt, capture the imagination of an entire community,
我认为我们会看到突然爆发的货币， 抓住整个社区的想象力，
and then acquire value.
然后获得价值
I have some bad news, the other way [this] could go.
我有一个坏消息，另一种可能是
Some of these currencies will have monetary value and then fade into nothingness again.
其中一些货币将具有货币价值， 然后再次淡入虚无
A bubbling cauldron full of currencies where some rise to the surface, and then sink down quickly.
一个冒泡的大锅，里面装满了各种货币， 有些上升到表面，有些则迅速下沉
Some stay afloat [for the long term]. I think Bitcoin will be one of the powerful ones.
有些货币能长期维持下去， 我认为比特币将是最强大的货币之一
I'm not sure about Dogecoin yet, but it is looking pretty promising.
我还不确定狗狗币会怎样， 但是看起来很有希望
I think it is very interesting how this community demonstrated to the world what marketing can do,
我觉得这个社区很有趣， 向世界展示了营销可以做什么，
by having a positive and charitable spirit.
通过具有积极和慈善的精神
That is the new world I think we will live in, within a couple of decades.
我认为这就是我们将在几十年内创造的新世界
It will be a very interesting world.
这将是一个非常有趣的世界
That is what I wanted to talk about today, the role of currency as language and form of societal [expression].
这就是我今天要谈的， 货币作为社会[表达]的语言和形式
Thank you so much! [Applause]
非常感谢！ [掌声]